abbvie.com 2019-12-24

# Privacy | AbbVie

This online Privacy Notice (“Privacy Notice”) explains how AbbVie Inc., 1 North Waukegan Rd., North Chicago, IL 60064 (“AbbVie”) handles personal information about you (“Personal Information”) provided to us through websites, mobile sites, mobile applications, third parties, services and products controlled by AbbVie, and any other online or offline interaction with AbbVie, that link to this Privacy Notice (collectively, “AbbVie Services”).

## Personal Information we collect

The types of Personal Information that we may collect for the purposes described in this Privacy Notice are described in this section and include Personal Information that you provide to us, Personal Information that we collect automatically when you use AbbVie Services, and Personal Information that we collect from third parties. Examples of Personal Information include name, address, telephone number, and email address. When this information is combined with any information on health or medical status, we refer to the resulting information as “health-related information.” We collect your health-related information on the AbbVie Services only if you provide it, with your consent, to provide certain AbbVie Services, or if required by law.

### Information you provide during registration or in response to questionnaires

You do not have to register for a service or program to receive much of the information available through AbbVie Services. However, some of our content is available only to registered or identified users and will require you to set up a profile or provide specific information about yourself in order to provide you the service.

AbbVie collects Personal Information that you provide on AbbVie Services, for example, through an enrollment form in order to register for AbbVie programs and services, to receive marketing products and information, contact AbbVie customer service, or respond to AbbVie questionnaires or surveys. This could include the following categories of Personal Information:

  * Direct identifiers, including name and contact Information such as your address, phone number, or email address;
  * Registration information, such as your username and password;
  * Health-related information, insurance and demographic information in the context of a patient support program, survey or questionnaire;
  * Income and demographic information when you request financial assistance for one of our products;
  * Remuneration information when you provide a service to AbbVie in your capacity as a health care professional;
  * Employment, education and other background information when you inquire about employment with AbbVie; and
  * Professional, clinical practice and educational background when you participate in an AbbVie sponsored program, research or survey in your capacity as a health care professional.

### Personal Information you submit during other interactions with AbbVie

You may contact AbbVie to ask questions, discuss your concerns, or report issues regarding our products. If you communicate with or request information from AbbVie, you may be prompted to provide your contact information as well as any health-related information and/or Personal Information that is relevant to your request.

### Information that may be collected automatically

**IP address**

We may record the Internet Protocol (“IP”) address of your computer or other electronic device when you visit the AbbVie Services. An IP address identifies the electronic device you use to access the Sites, which allows us to maintain communication with your computer as you move about AbbVie Services and to customize content.

**Cookies and other tracking technologies**

We collect information about your use of AbbVie Services through tracking technologies such as cookies and web beacons. A “cookie” is a unique numeric code that is transferred to your computer to track your interests and preferences and to recognize you as a return visitor. A “Web beacon” is a transparent graphic image placed on a website, email or advertisement that enables the monitoring of things such as user activity and site traffic. These technologies help remember your preferences and allow us to bring you the content and features that are likely to be of greatest interest to you on the basis of “clickstream” data that shows your previous activities on AbbVie Services.  

You can disable cookies through your browser. Please note that some cookies are essential to the functioning of our websites and deleting or disabling them on your browser will reduce the site’s functionality.  

For site analytics tracking, we use Google Analytics and Adobe Analytics. The data we collect through these cookies will be used to understand our website usage. We may also add your website usage data to the profile we maintain about you. If you do not want your data used with Google Analytics for these purposes, you can install the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. If you do not want your data used with Adobe Analytics for these purposes, you can opt-out by visiting <https://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html>.  

To learn more about cookies and other tracking technologies, including how to disable them, please visit <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>.

**Mobile tracking**

Some AbbVie Services are available either as mobile applications or mobile sites that you can use on your mobile device. If you use a mobile device to access and use the AbbVie Services, we may collect the following mobile-specific information in addition to the other information described above: device or advertising ID, device type, hardware type, media access control (“MAC”) address, international mobile equipment identity (“IMEI”), the version of your mobile operating system, the platform used to access or download the AbbVie sites and applications (e.g., Apple, Google, Amazon, Windows), location information and usage information about your device and your use of the AbbVie Services.

### Information collected from other sources

We may combine Personal Information about you from a visit to one AbbVie site with information about you from visits to other AbbVie Services. We may also combine information about you that is collected through the AbbVie Services with information that we have collected offline, as well as with information provided to us by third parties. Third parties from which we collect Personal Information include publicly available sources, third party data vendors, health care providers and health insurance companies, and third-party partners and collaborators.

[Top]

## How we use Personal Information

We collect and use your Personal Information for the business and commercial purposes of providing  you the services you request, communicating with you, improving your experience on the AbbVie Services, and generally improving our products and services and for other internal business purposes, as described in more detail below.  

### Providing programs and services you request

If you choose to register for one of our AbbVie Services, we use the Personal Information that you provide through AbbVie Services to respond to your questions, provide you the services you request and offer an optimal customer experience, to perform our contractual obligations, or perform an action based on your consent.  

### Marketing

You may also choose to receive marketing information from AbbVie, such as offers regarding AbbVie’s products or services, invitations to participate in surveys about our products, or notifications about special promotions. In such cases, we will use your contact and other Personal Information to send you marketing information. Instructions on how you can opt-out from marketing communications are included in each marketing communication you receive. You can also email us at [privacyoffice@abbvie.com](mailto:privacyoffice@abbvie.com). You can opt-out at any time.

### Customized user experiences

The Personal Information that you provide may be used to create customized offers, information, or services tailored to your interests and preferences. Also, we may use your IP address and the data that we obtain automatically through the use of cookies or similar tracking technologies to make our AbbVie Services easier to use and navigate,  to personalize the content provided on AbbVie Services by anticipating the information and services that may be of interest to you, and to personalize and improve our interactions with you by making the information we provide more relevant to you. In some cases, we collect this information pursuant to your consent. In other cases, we collect this information for our legitimate business interest to optimize and customize user experiences.

### Business and product improvement

In order to discover new facts that could help AbbVie better understand customer needs and help improve, develop, and evaluate product services, materials, programs, and treatments, AbbVie analyzes the information that you have provided for its legitimate interests in business and product improvement.

### Site analytics and improvement

We may use the information that you provide and the information we collect automatically about your use of the AbbVie Services to monitor user traffic patterns and preferences for our legitimate business interests of improvement, analytics and optimization of the AbbVie Services.

### Data use and retention

We will only keep Personal Information as long as necessary for the fulfillment of the purposes outlined in this Privacy Notice, except if otherwise required by applicable laws or legal orders.

[Top]

We only share your Personal Information with third parties as described below. We do not sell or rent Personal Information to third parties for their own marketing purposes.  

### Third-party advertising and online behavioral advertising

You may be provided with online advertisements of AbbVie products and services on third-party websites and mobile services that are tailored to you, for example, on the basis of information that you provide to AbbVie or a third-party website you are visiting, or of your browsing activity, purchases, or interests. These types of tailored online advertisements may come through several sources, as described in this section.

We may share with our advertising service providers certain device information that we have obtained from cookies and other tracking technologies on our AbbVie Services.

Some AbbVie Services participate in online behavioral advertising (this is also sometimes called re-target advertising or interest-based advertising). You can identify these sites by the “Advertising Choices” link in the footer. Our advertising network partners may place and use cookies on AbbVie websites and on other third-party sites to collect information about your activities in order to provide you with online advertisements that are based on your interests. When an AbbVie online behavioral advertisement is delivered to you, you will see an “[Ad Choices](http://info.evidon.com/pub_info/6678?v=1&nt=0&nw=false)” icon. Clicking on the icon or link will take you to a website where you can manage or opt-out of the use of data about your browsing history that is used for the delivery of online behavioral advertisements. If you opt-out, you may still see advertisements online, including advertisements from AbbVie that are based on other information (e.g., based on the content of the page being viewed rather than your prior clickstream activity). In some cases, data may still be collected about your browsing activity by these third-party advertisers, but they will not use this data to deliver advertisements that are based on your past online browsing behavior. You can also opt-out now by clicking [here](http://info.evidon.com/pub_info/6678?v=1&nt=0&nw=false).

You may also opt out of certain online behavioral advertising on the Digital Advertising Alliance’s consumer choice tool, which is available at [https://optout.aboutads.info](https://optout.aboutads.info/), and the Network Advertising Initiative’s tool, which is available at <https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>.  

Some web browsers may transmit “do-not-track” signals to web services with which the browser communicates. As of the effective date of this Privacy Notice, an industry standard has not yet been established on how to respond to these signals. Therefore, AbbVie does not currently respond to these signals. As discussed above, you can opt-out from advertisers that use your browsing history to deliver online behavioral advertisements.

### Affiliates, vendors and suppliers

We have relationships with various vendors and suppliers, including our affiliated companies, who help us operate our business and for whom it may be necessary to have access to your Personal Information in the course of providing services to AbbVie. We will not authorize these parties to use your Personal Information for any purpose that is not related to AbbVie’s business operation, and we require them to handle your Personal Information collected through the AbbVie Services in accordance with appropriate contractual privacy and security provisions.

### Co-branded services

We may partner with other companies to provide you with content or services on a joint or “co-branded” basis. At a co-branded site, you will see both the AbbVie logo and the logo of the co-branding partner displayed on your screen. To access the services available on a co-branded site, you may have to complete a new online registration form, and this registration information may be shared with AbbVie’s co-branding partners. You should read the individual privacy policies of our co-branding partners, as they may differ in some respects from ours. Reading these policies will help you to make an informed decision about whether to provide your information to a given site.

### Product reports

If you contact AbbVie regarding your experience in using one of our products, we may use the information that you provide in submitting reports to the U.S. Food and Drug Administration and as otherwise required of us by law. We also may use the information to contact the prescribing physician to follow up regarding an unexpected event involving the use of our product.

### Legal rights and obligations

In certain limited circumstances, AbbVie may need to disclose your Personal Information in order to comply with a legal obligation or demand, such as to comply with reporting obligations to our governing regulatory authorities regarding the safety of our pharmaceutical products, or in connection with the sale or transfer of one of our product lines or divisions, which includes the services provided through one or more of the AbbVie Services. In such instances, we will take measures to protect your Personal Information to the extent possible. We also reserve the right to use Personal Information to investigate and prosecute users who violate our rules or who engage in behavior that is illegal or harmful to others or to others’ property.

[Top]

## Additional information for California residents

If you are a California resident, you have the right to receive specific information about how AbbVie collects, uses and discloses your Personal Information, and you may have specific rights with respect to your Personal Information. California-specific privacy requirements that are not addressed in other sections of this Privacy Notice are described in this section.

Consistent with the Personal Information we collect section above, we collect certain categories and specific pieces of information about individuals that are considered Personal Information. As detailed above, we may collect this Personal Information from you and other third parties. We collect, use and disclose Personal Information for the business and commercial purposes described in the How we use Personal Information and the When we share Personal Information sections above.

As a California resident, you have the right to request:

  * Information about the Personal Information that AbbVie has collected, used and disclosed about you over the previous 12 months, including: the categories of Personal Information collected; the categories of sources from which your Personal Information was collected; the business or commercial purposes for which AbbVie collected your Personal Information; the categories of your Personal Information that was disclosed for a business or commercial purpose; and the categories of third parties with whom AbbVie shared your Personal Information;

  * The specific Personal Information that AbbVie has collected about you over the previous 12 months; and

  * To have your Personal Information deleted.

Should you exercise any of your privacy rights as a California resident, AbbVie will not discriminate against you by offering you different pricing or products, or by providing you with a different level or quality of products, based solely upon this request. Certain AbbVie Services, however, may require your consent to have your Personal Information shared with AbbVie to provide the service or to allow us to use and disclose your Personal Information to provide the Service. When you exercise your rights, you may lose access to certain aspects of AbbVie Services that require your Personal Information to perform the service.   

Please see the Your privacy choices section if you have questions or would like to make a request to exercise any of your rights.

[Top]

## Additional information for health care professionals

In addition to the Personal Information described in the Personal Information we collect section above, we collect the additional categories of Personal Information about health care professionals as described in this section. We also use, share and disclose Personal Information about health care professionals for the additional purposes described in the section in addition to the How we use Personal Information and the When we share Personal Information sections above.

### Additional Personal Information that AbbVie collects about health care professionals

We may collect Personal Information about health care professionals directly from the health care professional or from third-party sources, such as from the organization where the health care professional works, from publicly available sources, databases and websites, including social media platforms, and from third-party data vendors.

AbbVie may collect the following additional categories of Personal Information from health care professionals:

  * Professional details, such as resumes or other documents or forms provided directly to AbbVie, place of practice, job title, professional contact details, the medical specialty, professional license number, professional qualifications and scientific activities (such as previous clinical trial experience, activity on social media platforms or other websites, and participation in past or pending research studies with AbbVie and other companies), organizational or institutional affiliations, publication of academic or scientific research and articles, and membership in associations and boards. 

  * Personal Information provided to participate in AbbVie-sponsored or supported initiatives, such as AbbVie-sponsored clinical research and development activities, online or in-person seminars regarding product information and AbbVie services, educational events, and clinical information updates.

  * Payment and other transfers of value details received from your interactions with AbbVie, which may include, for example, contributions to costs of educational events (such as registrations fees, travel and accommodation expenses) and fees for services, including consultancy services.

### Additional uses of health care professional Personal Information

We use and disclose Personal Information of health care professionals for the following additional purposes: 

  * Complying with laws, regulations, or requirements imposed by industry codes of conduct to disclose or publish payment and other transfer of value data. These reporting activities will be based on a legal reporting obligation or our legitimate interest in complying with industry standards. 

  * For internal accounting and analysis in connection with AbbVie’s internal policies and rules, such as the AbbVie Code of Business Conduct, based on AbbVie’s legitimate interests in ensuring compliance with such policies and rules and protecting its interests and assets.

  * To administer, manage and improve our relationship with you, including through planning, organizing, and reviewing any collaboration with you, segmentation, analysis, and combining of such data to improve our understanding of and interactions with you and to contact you. We may also process your Personal Information to communicate to you about our products and programs, engage with you about scientific or educational programs, administer our patient support programs, respond to product orders, and provide product samples. We process your Personal Information for these purposes based on our legitimate interests in administering, managing and improving our relationship with you.

  * If you or your institution have entered into a consulting, professional services, or other type of agreement with us, we will process your Personal Information for the performance of our contract with you.

[Top]

## Privacy of children

AbbVie does not knowingly collect or use any personal information directly from children (we define “children” as minors younger than 13) on AbbVie Services. AbbVie Services are not directed to or intended to interact directly with children. We do not knowingly allow children to order our products, to communicate with us, or to use any of our online Services. All AbbVie Services that support children are directed to and are communicated with parents and guardians only. If you are a parent or guardian and become aware that your child has provided us with information, please contact us using one of the methods in the  Your privacy choices section, and we will work with you to address this issue.

[Top]

## Your privacy choices

You may contact us at any time if you have questions about this Privacy Notice or the Personal Information we collect about you. You can also opt-out or unsubscribe from any of our programs or services.

Please submit your privacy requests or inquiries here. Please contact us by clicking on the “Contact” link, by using the AbbVie contact information on the AbbVie mobile application, by emailing us at [privacyoffice@abbvie.com](mailto:privacyoffice@abbvie.com) or by calling us toll-free at 1-800-255-5162. Alternatively, you may send a letter to the following address:

AbbVie Customer Service  
Attn: Privacy  
Department 36M  
1 N. Waukegan Road  
North Chicago, IL  60064-6163

In all communications to AbbVie, please include the email address used for registration (if applicable), the website address, mobile application, or the specific AbbVie program to which you provided Personal Information (e.g., AbbVie.com), and a detailed explanation of your request. If you would like to delete, amend, or correct your Personal Information and are contacting us by email, please put “Deletion Request” or “Amendment/Correction Request” in the subject line of the email. We will respond to all reasonable requests in a timely manner and may need to further confirm your identity in order to process certain requests.

### Additional rights under European Union Data Protection Law

Under applicable data protection law, you may be entitled to request access to and/or rectify, block, or delete your Personal Information, transmission to another controller, withdraw your consent at any time (this does not affect the lawfulness of previous data processing activities), or object to any use of Personal Information. If AbbVie will not be able to provide the requested information or make the change you request, you will be provided with reasons for such decision. Under local law you are also entitled to lodge a complaint with your local data protection authority. 

You have the right to object to the processing activities described in this Privacy Notice that are based on our legitimate interests.

Please submit your privacy inquiries here. Alternatively, you may send a letter to Knollstraße, 67061Ludwigshafen, Germany (attention: EU DPO).

[Top]

## Data security

AbbVie maintains reasonable technical, administrative and physical controls to secure any Personal Information collected through the AbbVie Services. However, there is always some risk that an unauthorized third party could intercept an Internet transmission, or that someone will find a way to thwart our security systems. We urge you to exercise caution when transmitting Personal Information over the Internet, especially your health-related information. AbbVie cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will not gain access to your Personal Information; therefore, when submitting Personal Information to AbbVie Services, you must weigh both the benefits and the risks.

[Top]

This Privacy Notice does not apply to AbbVie Services that do not link to this Privacy Notice, or to third-party websites to which AbbVie Services may link. AbbVie Services may use social media plug-ins (e.g., the Facebook “Like” button, “Share to Twitter” button) to enable you to easily share information with others. When you visit AbbVie Services, the operator of the social plug-in can place a cookie on your computer or other electronic device that enables that operator to recognize individuals who have previously visited our sites. If you are logged into the social media website (e.g., Facebook, Twitter) while browsing on our AbbVie Site, the social media plug-in allows that social media website to receive information that you have visited our AbbVie Site. The social media plug-in also allows the social media website to share information about your activities on our AbbVie Site with other users of their social media website. These sharing settings are managed by the social media website and governed by its privacy policy. 

[Top]

## Accessing our sites globally

This site is owned and operated by AbbVie in the United States, but the information you provide will be accessible to our affiliates, vendors, and suppliers in other countries. Furthermore, if you are visiting this site from a country other than the United States, your communication with us will necessarily result in the transfer of information across international borders. These territories may not provide a level of protection to Personal Information equivalent to that provided by your home country. Our company maintains an Inter-Affiliate Data Transfer Agreement, which is based on the EU model contract for data transfers to controllers and covers all Personal Information transfers between AbbVie Inc. and its affiliates worldwide to ensure the adequate protection of your Personal Information. A copy can be obtained by sending an email to [privacyoffice@abbvie.com](mailto:privacyoffice@abbvie.com). Any transfers of Personal Information to third parties outside the EEA will be conducted in compliance with the international data transfer restrictions that apply under EU data protection laws, including, where appropriate, through the use of EU model contracts for data transfers to processors.

[Top]

## Changes to our Privacy Notice

We will collect and use Personal Information only in the manner described in the Privacy Notice in effect when the Personal Information was collected. However, and subject to any applicable consent requirements, we reserve the right to change the terms of this Privacy Notice at any time. Any changes to this Privacy Notice will be reflected on this page with a new effective date. AbbVie encourages you to review this Privacy Notice regularly for any changes. Any Personal Information collected upon your continued use of AbbVie Services will be handled in accordance with the currently posted Privacy Notice.

Check this Privacy Notice regularly, as we may change or update portions of this Privacy Notice from time to time, subject to any applicable consent requirements. Any changes will be promptly posted to this page and accompanied by a new effective date at the top of this page.

[Top]

### Other countries:
